Finding Aid for William Gepford papers, 1950-2008
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
William Gepford papers 1950-2008 1985-2004
Gepford, William.
2008098 Aa 2
Presbyterian minister actively involved in bridging the Christian and Islamic faiths based in Dearborn, Michigan. The collection consists mainly of records documenting his interfaith initiatives, writings, and correspondence.
2 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by William Gepford (donor no. 9913 ) in 2007 and 2009.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
The Reverend William George Gepford (January 12, 1927) was born in Kansas City, Missouri. He received a degree in electrical engineering from Colorado State University, his B.D. from McCormick Theological Seminary, and his Masters of Education from the University of Colorado, and his Doctor of Science in Theology from the San Francisco Theological Seminary.
In his efforts to increase understanding between the Christian and Islamic faiths, he has traveled extensively and held a variety of positions both in the United States and overseas. He currently maintains an office at the Littlefield Presbyterian Church in Dearborn, Michigan.
The collection consists of two series: Professional Papers and Visual Materials. These series document William Gepford's efforts to bridge the Muslim and Christian faiths, both within his own ministry as well as international efforts. These efforts include seminars, interfaith worship services, and international initiatives. The collection also documents his everyday activities with the Presbyterian Church and interaction with the Detroit community.
Subjects:
Arab Americans--Michigan--Dearborn.; Clergy--Michigan--Dearborn.; Dearborn (Mich.)--Church history.; Gepford, William.; Littlefield Presbyterian Church (Dearborn, Mich.)
Genre Terms:
DVDs.; Videotapes.
- Professional Papers
  - Correspondence 1957-2008
    - Congressional 1980, 1984-1998, 2003, 2007-2008 (Box 1)
    - Detroit/Windsor Refugee Coalition 1993-1995 (Box 1)
    - Local 1979-1988 (Box 1)
    - Local 1989-2008 (Box 1)
    - National and Overseas 1957, 1963, 1973-1974, 1979-1989 (Box 1)
    - National and Overseas 1990-1994, 1996-1998, 2001-2003, 2006-2008 (Box 1)
    - Presbyterian Church 1957, 1963, 1974, 1980-1981, 1983-1986 (Box 1)
    - Presbyterian Church 1987-1996, 1998-1999, 2002, 2006 (Box 1)
  - Interfaith Initiatives 1979-2007
    - American-Arab Anti-Discrimination Committee (ADC) 1992-2007 (Box 1)
    - Arab Americans in Detroit 1983-1988 (Box 1)
    - Arab Ministry 1980-1989, 1991, 1994-1999, 2002, 2005-2007 (Box 1)
    - Church Councils 1989, 1991-1992, 1994, 2000, 2002, 2007 (Box 1)
    - Dearborn Public Schools lectures 1986, 1991, 1999-2002 (Box 1)
    - Detroit 300 Spirituality Day 2000-2001 (Box 1)
    - Detroit Parliament of World Religions 1997-1999 (Box 1)
    - Dignitary Visits 1988-1991 (Box 1)
      (Dr. Kenneth Cragg, Hassan Khaled, Grand Mufti of Lebanon)
    - General 1983-2000 (Box 1)
    - General 2001-2007 (Box 1)
    - Interfaith AIDS Service Committee 1996-1999 (Box 1)
    - International Efforts 1983-2001 (Box 1)
    - Islamic Advisory Committee 1986-1988 (Box 1)
    - Middle East 1980, 1986, 1990-1994, 1996-1999, 2001-2004 (Box 1)
    - National Council of the Churches of Christ in the U.S.A. 1980, 1983-1992, 1997 (Box 1)
    - Presbyterian Middle East Advisory Committees 1991-1993, 1995 (Box 1)
    - Religious Resources 1988-1998 (Box 2)
    - Thanksgiving Celebration 1989-2007 (Box 2)
    - Worship Services 1993, 1995, 1999, 2001-2002, 2005 (Box 2)
  - Other materials 1950-2007
    - Biographical information, resumes, etc. 1950, 1972-1992, 2007 (Box 2)
    - Clippings 1986, 1990-2005 (Box 2)
    - Detailed chronology of Minutes of Activities and responsibilities 2000 (Box 2)
    - McCormick Theological Seminary 1984, 1990-1994, 2007 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous: include other organizational affiliations 1979, 1989, 1991-1992, 1995, 1999-2006 (Box 2)
    - Speaking engagements 1980, 1984-1989 (Box 2)
    - Speaking engagements 1990-1991 (Box 2)
    - Speaking engagements 1992-1993 (Box 2)
    - Speaking engagements 1994-2006 (Box 2)
    - Writings, Interfaith 1989-2007 (Box 2)
    - Writings, Littlefield "Life" Newsletter Reflections 1990-2007 (Box 2)
    - Writings 1985, 1994 (Box 2)
    - Writings, miscellaneous 1985-1994 (Box 2)
- Visual Materials
  - Photographs, 1980, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Videocassette Tapes
    - Littlefield Presbyterian Church, Sunday Worship Service October 20, 2002, VHS (Box 2)
    - Littlefield Presbyterian Church, Christians and Muslims, Dialog October, 2002, VHS (Box 2)
  - DVDs
    - Littlefield Presbyterian Church, 75th Anniversary April 24, 2005, 2 optical disks DVDs (Box 2)